So far we've been working with the state value function for a policy.
到目前为止 我们介绍的都是策略的状态值函数
For each state s,
对于每个状态 s
it yields the expected discounted return If the agent starts in state
它都会生成智能体从状态 s 开始时的期望折扣回报
as and then uses the policy to choose its actions for all time steps.
然后使用该策略选择所有时间步的动作
You've seen a few examples and know how to
你已经看过几个示例 知道如何计算
calculate the state value function corresponding to a policy.
对应某个策略的状态值函数
In this concept, we'll define a new type of
在这部分 我们将定义一种新的值函数
value function known as the action-value function.
称之为动作值函数
This value function is denoted with a lowercase q instead of v.
这种值函数表示为小写的 q 而不是 v
While the state values are a function of the environment state,
状态值是环境状态的函数
the action values are a function of the environment state and the agent's action.
而动作值是环境状态和智能体动作的函数
For each state s and action a,
对于每个状态 s 和动作 a
the action value function yields
动作值函数都会生成
the expected discounted return If the agent starts in state
智能体从状态 s 开始并选择动作 a 时
s then chooses action a and
获得的期望折扣回报
then uses a policy to choose its actions for all future time steps.
然后使用该策略选择所有未来时间步的动作
Just like with the state value function,
和状态值函数一样
it will help your intuition If you calculate this yourself.
自己计算该公式可以加深理解
In the case of the state value function,
对于状态值函数
we kept track of the value of each state with the number on the grid.
我们用网格中的数字记录每个状态的值
We'll do something similar with the action-value function,
对于动作值函数 我们将采取相似的方法
where we now need up to four values for each state,
现在对于每个状态 我们最多需要四个值
each corresponding to a different action.
每个对应不同的动作
These four numbers correspond to
这四个数字对应相同的状态
the same state but the one on top corresponds to action up;
但是顶部的数字对应向上动作
the one on the right, corresponds to moving right before following the policy and so on.
右侧数字对应在遵守策略向右移动前的动作 等等
You'll see this soon.
很快你就会明白
So with the exception of the terminal state,
将最终状态除外
I've broken up the figure to leave a space for keeping
我拆分了该图表 以便留出空间
track of the value corresponding to each possible state and action.
记录对应于每个潜在状态和动作的值
And let's see if we can calculate some action values.
看看我们能否计算某些动作值
We'll begin with the state here.
我们将从这个状态开始
Let's calculate the value corresponding to this state and action down.
计算对应于该状态和动作的值
So the agent starts in this state,
智能体从该状态开始
takes action down and receives a reward of negative one.
向下采取动作并获得奖励 -1
Then for every time step in the future,
然后对于未来的每个时间步
it just follows the policy until it reaches the terminal state.
它都遵守该策略 直到抵达最终状态
We can then add up all the rewards that it encountered
我们将一路上遇到的所有奖励相加
along the way and when we do that, we get zero.
结果是 0
So this zero corresponds to the action value
0 对应智能体从该状态开始
for this state where the agent started and action down.
并采取向下动作时的动作值
Let's try calculating another actual value,
我们再计算另一个动作值
this time corresponding to this state and action up.
这次对应这个状态和向上动作
So the agent starts in the state and takes action up,
智能体从该状态开始并采取向上动作
and it received a reward of negative one.
获得奖励 -1
Then it just follows a policy for all future time steps.
然后在所有未来时间步都遵守策略
We add up the reward it collected along
我们将一路上收集的奖励相加
the way and this yields a cumulative reward of one.
结果是累积奖励为 1
So this one corresponds to the action value for this state and action up.
这个值对应该状态和向上动作的动作值
So you can continue and do this for every state-action pair that makes sense.
你可以继续下去并为所有合理的状态动作对完成这一计算流程
And when you do this, you get this action-value function.
当你这么计算时 就会获得这个动作值函数
I highly encourage you to calculate and check these values yourself.
强烈建议你自己计算并检查这些值
Before moving on, it's important to revisit some information that you learned earlier.
在继续学习新内容之前 有必要复习下之前学到的某些知识
Remember that we have the notation v_star to refer to the optimal state value function.
注意 我们用 v* 表示最优状态值函数
Similarly, we'll refer to the optimal action value function as q_star.
同样 我们用 q* 表示最优动作值函数